Animesh Dhengre

animesh.codes

How to reach me:

+91-9131930854

@ Email:

dhengreani18@gmail.com

in Linkedin:

@animesh-dhengre

Github:

@DhengreAni18



Civil Lines, Raipur (C.G) 492001

Personal Profile

I am a software developer with robust problem-solving skills and proven experience in creating and designing software in a test-driven environment.

Achievements

- Won first prize at Codeutsava Hackathon 2020 and qualified for SIH '20
- Among top 50K contributors in Hacktoberfest 2018

Education

National Institute of Technology, Raipur (C.G)

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology

- Enrolled since April 2017 to present
- Core subjects as Data Structures, Web technologies, Database.
- · Expected year of Graduation 2021.

Jatan Devi Daga H.S School

Senior Secondary School

• Attended from Jan. 2015 to Jan 2016

Projects

Online Realtime Auction 1

- An online web based real time auction app for conducting auctions.
- Developed server on nodejs using socketio, which interact with bidder and auctioneer on realtime basis.
- Used firebase realtime database for storing data which resist delays during auction.

Technologies used: Nodejs, SocketIO, Firebase

DevNetwork 17

- A Social networking website for developers with functionality to create and view profiles of the users.
- Developed over MVC architecture giving users ability to post on feed and to like or comment...

Technologies used: MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, **NodeJS**

Work Experience

Backend Developer Intern

ASC ALLSOFT IT Pvt. Ltd. May 2019 to July 2019

- Developed backend server using Nodeis and SocketIO.
- · Worked with Firebase realtime database to store data and to show real time updates to the users.
- User Authentication using Redis.

Web Developer

Eclectika - NIT Raipur July 2018 to Present

- Developed website for Year 2019, 2020
- Worked with Bootstrap, CSS, and HTML to create visual designs including responsive design
- Used JS to parse data from JSON API to show data in the Event section of the website.

Professional Skills

Coding Languages:

Frameworks:

JavaScript, HTML/CSS, Java

Nodejs, ReactJS, Bootstrap, SocketIO, MongoDB

Tools/Technologies:

Firebase, Git, Postman

Systems:

Linux, Windows, Mac OS